Principal Data Scientist / Mentor

- 801.472.6238
- mikedkelly@gmail.com
- ♀ Lindon / UT
- LinkedIn
- % YouTube

ABOUT ME

Avid technologist, life-long learner, and strategist in the fields of data science and training.

I have spent the last several decades producing data insights in the fields of healthcare, nuclear power, and enterprise applications with responsibilities ranging from individual contribution to managing multimillion-dollar organizations.

SKILLS

9 / 10

Predictive Modeling

10/10

Mentoring / Training

9 / 10

Agile Leadership

9 / 10

Product Management

9 / 10

Instructional Design

EXPERIENCE

Principal Data Scientist / Mentor

Optum / Eden Prairie, MN / Dec 2015 - Present

Mentoring, Product Management, & Data Science Research.

- Created and delivered data science training to 250+ employees
- Participated in disease progression research projects
- Managed \$3.2M capital budget and three agile teams
- Built Medicare data transforming application to save \$2M annually

Data Analyst / Director of Training

DevonWay / Holiday, UT / 2009 - 2015

Designed, developed, and delivered business operations training programs to the nuclear power generation industry.

- Constructed and managed \$10K \$300K training projects
- Mentored business owners to build operational analytics
- Recruited and hired a department of Masters- and PhD-level experts

Additional Notable Career Positions

Co-inventor of patent 10,621,013 – AI Deployment Platform

Data Architect – Remedy Informatics (UK Cancer Research)

Senior Instructor / Worldwide Certifications Manager – Novell 1995-1999

EDUCATION

B.S./ Aeronautical Engineering *California Polytechnic, S.L.O., CA* 1989